Finding Aid for Stearns collection of Musical Instruments records, 1897-1921
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Stearns Collection of Musical Instruments records 1897-1921
Stearns Collection of Musical Instruments.
1 linear foot
87314 Bimu C450 2
Records, 1897-1921,of the Stearns Collection of Musical Instruments of the University of Michigan; include correspondence and other papers relating to the development of the collection; also scrapbooks,1890's,containing illustrations of musical instruments. Correspondents include: Francis W. Kelsey, Albert A. Stanley, Frederick Stearns, Frederick Kimball Stearns, George R. Swain, Levi D. Wines, and Dean C. Worcester.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was acquired from the University of Michigan Library (donor no. 1278 ).
The record group is open without restriction
Acquired in 1899 as a gift from Frederick Stearns, a Detroit manufacturer of pharmaceuticals, the collection originally contained 904 rare, old or simply unusual musical instruments from around the world. Further gifts from Stearns and others have considerably enlarged the collection, which was housed in Hill Auditorium for many years and is now displayed at the School of Music.
The records include correspondence regarding the acquisition and care of the instruments (1897-1921), annual reports, a statement of loan policy, and articles by Robert Austin Warner on the history and content of the collection. Also included are two scrapbooks containing bills and letters regarding Stearns' acquisitions, clippings, and illustrations from 1890s catalogs.
Subjects:
Music--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Musical instruments.
Contributors:
Kelsey, Francis W. (Francis Willey), b. 1858.; Stanley, Albert A. (Albert Augustus), 1851-1932.; Stearns, Frederick, 1831-1907.; Swain, George Robert, 1866-1947.; Wines, Levi Douglas, 1852-1938.; Worcester, Dean C. (Dean Conant), 1866-1924.
Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.
- Records
  - Correspondence
    - 1897-1904, 12 folders (Box 1)
    - 1907 (Box 1)
    - 1920-1921 (Box 1)
  - Labels from Musical Instruments (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports (Box 1)
  - Friends of the Stearns Collection (Box 1)
  - Loan Policy (Box 1)
  - Evaluation Report on Bowed String Musical Instruments (Box 1)
  - Student Paper Describing Stearns Collection (Box 1)
  - Robert A. Warner Papers on Stearns Collection (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Musical Instrument Scrapbooks, circa 1890-1910 (Box 1)
    (Volumes VI and VII; include correspondence, clippings and catalog illustrations)
- Publications
  - Brochures, undated (Box 1)
  - Centennial Celebration: A Sketch Book, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Research News (Stearns Feature), 1973 (Box 1)
  - Stearns @ Hill, Fall 2004 (Box 1)
  - The Stearns Newsletter, 1986-2006 (Box 1)